Hello everyone, how are you all? I am your
personal advisor Amit Raj Sharma and you are
watching Yudh Real. At the very
beginning of the video, I want to inform you that
if you want to understand the details of the first option of the Guaranteed Income for Tomorrow plan,
which is called the Lumpsum option, then you must watch this
thumbnail which is at the top of your screen,
go to the Life Insurance playlist and watch it without skipping
because if you skip the details, you will
miss something.
Its link is also given in the description of the video. Let's
start today's video and know the
details. The second option of ICICI Prudential Life
Insurance Company Limited's Guaranteed Income
for Tomorrow plan, which is
called the Income option, which is also called the Income Plan option.
Talking about the entry limit,
we will subtract the positive term from the minimum entry of 18. For the
minimum entries limit,
people up to 60 years of age can take the plan. Talking about the
maturity limit further, the
minimum premium is 18 years and maximum is 73 years.  The
limit is Rs. 30,000. You will have to
pay a minimum premium of Rs. 10000 plus tax.
Now, when it comes to the premium
payment term and policy term, the
premium payment term option is
available from 5 years to 12 years,
and the policy term option is
available from 6 years to 13 years. The income period
option is available for 5 years, 7 years, and 10 years.
According to this, you will be
able to choose the premium payment term and the
income benefit period. When does it start?
From the next year after the completion of 1 year of premium payment, that is, when 2 years are completed,
then you can avail guaranteed income benefit in two ways, yearly and monthly.
In this plan, you
also get the option of a pay date, that is, if you want to
start getting income benefit from the date of your birthday or your wedding anniversary, then
you will be able to do so. The rate of income benefit will be
this.  It will depend on your policy term,
premium payment,
benefit pay, and period.
According to that, the basic life cover
in the plan will be
10 times your premium, which we call the term. So, let's
talk about death benefit.
See, the submersible liability, as I
told you, is 10 times the analyzed premium. Let's
compare this till the
date of death. If we subtract the
extra charges and taxes from the premium paid, then the
total paid premium
comes out to be 105%. Then we
compare it. We multiply the annual
guaranteed income benefit with the
death benefit factor.
Whichever is higher among the three is the
benefit that your nominee gets.
If death occurs during the income benefit period,
your nominee will continue to receive the guaranteed income
benefit or if they wish, they can
also avail the lump sum benefit. To understand
everything, let's take an example. Let's assume
that Mr. A is aged here.
She is 30 years old and is taking a policy term of 11 years here. If
we take 11 years positive, then
with this she will get premium payment for 10 years
and the income benefit period is
also being taken for 10 years here, so
in such a situation, the annual basic
premium of Rs 50000, if we
multiply it by Rs 50000, then the basic life cover will come out
which will be Rs 5 lakh. If you
want this income benefit in annual installments, then
you have taken the mode here.
Okay, now we have done it and
calculated it here, then we came to know that the
income benefit which we will get every year,
we will start getting it as soon as the 12 years of the policy are completed,
which will be
Rs 1671. For 10 years, we will get Rs 10 lakh, 16710
total, this is the guaranteed benefit amount.
What is our total paid premium
here? Rs 5 lakh. Okay, now you can watch the
video on full screen
because  You have to see some information here, the
first column you are seeing here
where the red line has come, it is written here
annoy the premium which is of ₹50000
and in the column before this, by writing the policy
year, now in the next column here
you can see the maturity benefit, by
which we are saying guaranteed income which is of
₹1671, now the next column
here is your death benefit amount,
now you will see that till the seventh year of the policy, the
cover amount of death benefit remains ₹5
lakh, after that it
starts increasing, that is, if there is a death till 7 years, then
₹5 lakh will be received, after that it will
increase, to understand how the increase has happened,
we will have to take an example here,
but before that let me tell you
that to know the death benefit factor,
we will have to convert the policy term into months, there are
12 months in a year, so
132 months in 11 years  Done here,
now we assume that Mr. A
died after completion of 10 years of the policy i.e. after
completion of 120 months, in
such a situation the outstanding
months left would be 12, that is, if 12
more months had been completed then maturity would have been A, so
in such a situation our death benefit
factor that will come out will be
588.6%, we will tell you from where we got this, turn the
video
on the police screen again, here we have taken 10 years,
income period right and the
outstanding months left for the
completion of the policy may be 12, so
588.76% our death
benefit factor entered here, we have shared this entire PDF
on the Telegram channel also,
we have given the link in the description, you can
go there and check Big Boss, you will
get the link here, you will be able to do it through that also, so
here we have assumed that death has occurred in 10 years,
Mr., there is only one
basic life cover, 10 times the annual premium
That is 5 lakhs and if you see, the
total premium paid was only 500000, if we
withdraw 105% of it in 10 years then the
amount will be 525000. Now the guaranteed income
benefit which was ₹1671 annually, we will
withdraw
588.6% of it, so an
amount of Rs 598598.18 paise will be
given to only one nominee here and the
policy will be closed. If Mr. had
taken the income benefit here monthly, then
what would have been the monthly installment? So see, the amount of 1 lakh
671 is 103 percent of the old guaranteed income
benefit,
we will take it and multiply it by 12, I am sorry, we will
divide it by 12 because there were
12 months in a year, so he will get ₹8726.76 paise.
Okay, in this way the monthly
guaranteed income benefit will be withdrawn.
Talking about surrender value, then for at least 2 years of
continuous premium  It is mandatory to do this, only
after that you can surrender the policy.
Now let us assume that sir, you are
surrendering this policy here on completion of the sixth year of the policy, so the
premium paid here in 6 years will be
₹300000, in such a situation the
guaranteed surrender value factor will be
50%, so 50% of 3 lakhs will be
deducted here, that is,
Mr. A will get an amount of 1.5 lakhs
as surrender value. If he
surrenders the policy on completion of the sixth year, then
from where did you get the surrender value factor, watch the
video on full
screen to know, we took a policy term of 11 years,
our 6 years were completed, so
our guaranteed surrender value factor of 50% became A,
if we had surrendered the policy on the 10th year, then we would
not have got more than 90% of the paid value here, okay, which paid value is the
base premium, because the
example we have taken does
not include tax  You get a revival period of
five years in this. In this policy also,
along with this benefit, you also
get the benefit of reduced paid up, that is,
after paying the premium for 2 years, if you are
not paying the premium, then after the grace period, the
policy will be converted into reduced paid up policy. In
such a situation, the reduced paid up
effect will be calculated. The number of
premiums you have paid will be divided by the
number of premiums you have to
pay. Whatever benefits you will have,
you will just have to multiply them by the reduction factor.
You watched the video till the end,
thank you very much for that and the remaining
two options which are left, we will
understand them in the upcoming videos. Now you have to understand one thing yourself and
others also that insurance is
a protection and protection is never taken
incomplete. Thank you very much to
all of you.